Finding Aid for Mary P. Sinclair papers, 1967-1999
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Midland Plant, NRC hearings 1970-1983
  - Transcripts
    - Prehearing Conferences, NRC
      - Washington, D.C. January 9, 1978 [Milton Freeman for intervenors] (Box 31)
      - Washington, D.C. March 1, 1978 [Freeman for intervenors] (Box 31)
      - Bethesda, Md. March 2, 1978 (Box 31)
      - Bethesda, Md. April 13, 1978 (Box 31)
      - Washington, D.C. May 17, 1978 (Box 31)
      - Bethesda, Md. May 31, 1978 (Box 31)
      - Bethesda, Md. July 11, 1978 (Box 31)
      - Bethesda, Md. September 7, 1978 (Box 31)
      - Midland, Mi. December 14, 1978 (Box 32)
    - Deposition, Ronald Lee Erickson, NRC, Detroit, Mi. January 20, 1981 (Box 32)
    - Prehearing Conference, NRC, Midland, Mi. January 28, 1981 (Box 32)
    - Prehearing Conference, NRC, Midland, Mi. January 29, 1981 (Box 32)
    - Deposition, Harold D. Thornburg (Director, Division of Reactor Construction Inspection, Office of Inspection and Enforcement NRC) Bethesda, Md. February 20, 1981 (Box 32)
    - Prehearing Conference, NRC, Midland, Mi. April 27, 1981 (Box 32)
    - Evidentiary Hearings, NRC, ASLB, Midland, Mi.
      - Witness: Gilbert S. Keeley July 8, 1981 (Box 32)
      - Witness: Eugene J. Gallagher (Civil Engineer in the Division of Resident and Regional Reactor Inspection, Reactor Engineering Branch, Office of Inspection and Enforcement, NRC) July 15, 1981, 5 folders (Box 32)
      - Witnesses: James W. Cook (Vice President, Consumers Power Company); Eugene Gallagher; and Darl S. Hood (Senior Project Manager, Division of Licensing, Office of Nuclear Reactor Regulation, NRC) July 16, 1981 (Box 32)
      - Witnesses: Darl S. Hood; and Donald M. Turnbull (Senior Supervising Engineer, Site Quality Assurance Superintendent, Midland Project Quality Assurance Department, Consumers Power Company) July 17, 1981 (Box 32)
      - Witness: Stephen H. Howell (Executive Vice President, Consumers Power Company) August 4, 1981 (Box 32)
      - Witness: Ralph B. Peck (Consulting Engineer, employed by Bechtel with regard to geotechnical aspects of Midland Project site) August 6, 1981 (Box 32)
      - Witnesses: Ralph B. Peck; Joseph Kane (Principal Geotechnical Engineer, Geotechnical Engineering Section, Hydrologic and Geotechnical Engineering Branch, Division of Engineering, Office of Nuclear Reactor Regulation, NRC); and Hari Narain Singh (Civil Engineer, U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, Detroit, Michigan) August 7, 1981 (Box 33)
      - Witnesses: Joseph Kane; Hari N. Singh; and Darl Hood August 8, 1981 (Box 33)
      - Witness: John William Gilray (Principal Quality Assurance Engineer, Quality Assurance Branch, Office of Nuclear Reactor Regulation, NRC) August 10, 1981 (Box 33)
      - Witnesses: Alfred J. Hendron, Jr. (Consultant to Bechtel on soil stability, Professor, University of Illinois, Department of Civil Engineering); Hari N. Singh; and Joseph Kane August 11, 1981 (Box 33)
    - Meeting, Subcommittee on Midland Plant Units 1 and 2, Advisory Committee on Reactor Safeguards, NRC. Washington, D.C. February 2, 1982 (Box 33)
    - Meeting, Subcommittee on Midland Plant Units 1 and 2, ACRS, NRC, Washington, D.C. April 29, 1982, 3 folders (Box 33)
    - Oral Argument, ASLB Appeal Board, Bethesda, Md. May 13, 1982 (Box 33)
    - NRC Staff's Testimony. Witnesses: James G. Keppler (Regional Administrator of NRC's Region III office); Darl Hood; John Gilray; Ronald J. Cook (Senior Resident Inspector for the NRC at the Midland Plant); Ross B. Landsman (Inspector for the NRC, Region III at the Midland Plant); Ronald N. Gardner (Inspector for the NRC, Region III at the Midland Plant); and Wayne D. Shafer (Chief, Midland Section, Office of Special Cases for the NRC, Region III) October 29, 1982 (Box 33)
    - Evidentiary Hearings, ASLB, NRC, Midland, MI
      - Witnesses: Joseph Kane; and Donald Lewis (Acting Assistant Project Engineer and Engineering Group Supervisor for Licensing and Safety, Midland Nuclear Project, Bechtel Associates Professional Corporation) November 16, 1982 (Box 33)
      - Witnesses: Donald A. Sommers (Engineering Supervisor, Bechtel Associates Professional Corporation); Donald Evans; and John P. Bradley (Certified Consulting Meteorologist, Murray and Trettel, Inc., Northfield, Illinois) March 8, 1983 (Box 33)
      - Witnesses: Donald Evans; Donald Sommers; John Bradley; James Carson (Meteorologist, Division of Environmental Impact Studies, Argonne National Laboratory); and Dr. Steve Y.H. Tsai (Hydrologist, Division of Environmental Impact Studies, Argonne National Laboratory) March 9, 1983 (Box 33)
      - Witnesses: James Carson; James Y.H. Tsai; David A. Anderson, Assistant Project Engineer, Midland Project, Bechtel Corporation; David T. Perry, Section Head, Mechanical Nuclear Group, Design Production Department, Consumers Power Company; and Gerald B. Slade, Assistant Site Manager, Midland Plant, Consumers Power Company March 10, 1983 (Box 34)
      - Witnesses: John R. Ridgely, Aleck W. Serkiz, Ronald Wayne Hernan March 11, 1983, 6 folders (Box 34)
      - Supplemental Testimony of James G. Keppler with Respect to Quality Assurance, ASLB, NRC March 25, 1983 (Box 34)
      - Witnesses: John J. Harrison, Ronald Gardner, Ron Cook, Ross Landsman and Darl Hood September 21, 1983 (Box 34)
- Palisades Plant, NRC hearings 1971-1999 (0.7 lin. ft.)
  The Palisades Plant, NRC hearings series contains legal documents relating to the permit hearings for the Palisades Nuclear Power Plant, arranged chronologically.
  - Settlement Agreement between Intervenors and Consumers Power Company March 12, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Investigation of Palisades violations 1973-1975, 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Papers re. NRC hearings 1980, 6 folders (Box 16)
  - Fermi Plant
    - AEC material
      - Correspondence June-August, 1972, re. cracks in slab (Box 16)
    - Participation agreements between power companies
      - 1976 (Box 16)
      - 1977 (Box 16)
    - Robert Asberger correspondence 1978 (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous 1978 (Box 16)
  - Petition to Intervene 1979 (Box 34)
  - Pleadings 1979-1985 (Box 34)
  - NRC September 14, 1995 Request for More Information Consumers Power Co. response and attachments, October 16, 1995, 4 folders (Box 34)
  - NRC November 20, 1995; Request for More Information Consumers Power Co. response and attachments, December 10, 1995, 4 folders (Box 34)
    (Reports re: Unloading of Multi-Assembly Sealed Basket)
  - Correspondence and Inspection Reports re: Dry Cask Storage of Nuclear Waste 1997-1999, 4 folders (Box 34)
- Industries
  The Industries series contains files pertaining to Sinclair's interaction with industry, (particularly Dow Chemical Co. and Consumers Power Co.) Files are arranged alphabetically by company and hold company publications, newsletters and correspondence. This series contains material from the original accession only (pre-1981). Researchers interested in specific corporations should consult the Topical Files series in the later accession (boxes 22-27) under headings for those companies.
  - Bethlehem Steel (Box 16)
  - Consumers Power Company
    - General (Box 16)
    - Correspondence (Box 16)
    - Documents and information (Box 16)
    - Plans for meeting energy requirements 1972-1982 (Box 16)
    - Relations with the media (Box 16)
    - Memos (Box 16)
    - Environment (Box 16)
    - Report to SEC (Box 16)
  - Detroit Edison (Box 16)
  - Dow Chemical
    - General (Box 17)
    - Pruitt report (Box 17)
    - Publication on nuclear power (Box 17)
    - Radiation standards (Box 17)
    - Statement on corrosion treatment (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 17)
  - General Electric
    - Engineers (Box 17)
  - General Motors
    - Coal cleanup (Box 17)
  - Mitre Corporation
    - Public participation (Box 17)
  - Rand Corporation (Box 17)
  - Reserve Mining (Box 17)
- Radiation
  The Radiation series holds Sinclair's research about the effects of radiation. It consists largely of articles she collected on the topic, and very little work from her own hand. It is arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - Bertell
    - Low-level radiation hazards (Box 17)
  - Bioconcentration (Box 17)
  - Conference on Low-Level Radiation (Box 17)
  - Correspondence (Box 17)
  - DNA (Box 17)
  - Goffman, John W.
    - Affidavit (Box 17)
  - High-voltage transmission (Box 17)
  - Honicker v. Hendrie (Box 17)
  - Internal injury (Box 17)
  - Low-level radiation (Box 17)
  - Presentations (Box 17)
  - Pro-nuclear statements and letters (Box 17)
  - Radionudide bioconcentration data (Box 17)
  - Safety (Box 17)
  - Standards (Box 17)
  - Studies and analyses (Box 17)
  - Study groups (Box 17)
  - Testimony (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 17)
- Alternatives to nuclear fission
  Like the Radiation series, the Alternatives to nuclear fission series contains research documents on the topic of nuclear fission. There are, however, two substantial correspondence files which document Sinclair's 1971 campaign to make political leaders aware of alternative energy technologies. The files are arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - Coal technology (Box 17)
  - Fusion
    - S. J. Bushbaum statement November 11, 1971 (Box 17)
    - Correspondence, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Nuckolls and Wood
      - Unconventional approaches (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 17)
  - Gas and oil (Box 17)
  - Magazine: "Alternative Sources of Energy" (Box 17)
  - Natural gas (Box 18)
  - Solar energy
    - Richard McMath project (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 18)
- Mass Media 1970-1978
  The Mass Media Files (0.5 lin. ft.)are arranged alphabetically and contain documentation of Sinclair's attention to the coverage her projects were garnering in the media. Materials include correspondence with reporters, manuscript scripts and articles written by and about Sinclair, and some clippings, particularly in the Bay City Times folder.
  - ABC TV documentary May 31, 1973 (Box 18)
  - BBC 1971 (Box 18)
  - Bay City Times 1971-1976 (Box 18)
  - Christian Science Monitor, 1971 (Box 18)
  - Clear Creek 1971-1974 (Box 18)
  - ECO 1972-1974 (Box 18)
  - Michigan Contractor 1976 (Box 18)
  - Michigan Riparian 1974 (Box 18)
  - Midland Daily News 1970-1977 (Box 18)
  - National Observer 1973 (Box 18)
  - New World Article (Stan Wiggins) 1969-1971 (Box 18)
  - News releases 1973 (Box 18)
  - Nuclear Opponents 1974 (Box 18)
  - Radio 1971 (Box 18)
  - Tri-City Magazine 1970-1976 (Box 18)
  - TV documentaries (Box 18)
  - TV-radio spots undated (Box 18)
  - University of Michigan press proceedings 1977-1978 (Box 18)
  - Wayne State University 1978 (Box 18)
  - WMAQ-TV 1973 (Box 18)
  - WMPX 1971 (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous 1973-1976, 2 folders (Box 18)
- Topical files 1967-1999
  The Topical Files series (6.0 lin. ft.) contains files documenting Sinclair's work on various environmental issues and is arranged alphabetically, by topic. The later accession (Boxes 22-27), following Sinclair's own original arrangement of the folders, gathers together in this series topics which were separated into separate series in the original accession, such as "People file," "Government Agencies," "Industries," "Radiation," "Alternatives to nuclear fission," and "Mass media." It includes significant subseries on Dow Chemical Company, (including the Midland/Dow Citizens Advisory Panel), and Press (including comprehensive press coverage of the Midland controversies in the Midland Daily News and Ann Arbor News.)
  - Balloon release, Midland June 24, 1978 (Box 18)
  - Big Rock plant (Box 18)
  - Borton, Thomas
    - Susquehanna Communication Participation Study 1970 (Box 18)
  - Funding of interventions (Box 18)
  - Fundraising (Box 18)
  - March on Midland April, 1979 (Box 18)
  - National Emergency Core Cooling Systems Hearings (Box 18)
  - National hearings
    - Idaho Nuclear Corporation (Box 18)
    - Marble Hill, Indiana plant (Box 18)
  - Nuclear Education Conference
    - Proceedings February, 1971 (Box 18)
  - Nuclear power
    - Selection of major documents (Box 18)
  - Pro-nuclear papers
    - Cohen, Bernard L. (Box 18)
    - Draper, E. Linn (Box 18)
  - Rate withholding (Box 18)
  - Roman Catholic Church
    - Proposed policy statement on energy May, 1978 (Box 18)
  - Ross, M. and R. Williams paper 1977 (Box 18)
  - Sheffield waste disposal
    - Letters 1978 (Box 18)
    - Silkwood, Karen (Box 18)
    - Sinclair, Peter (drawings) (Box 18)
    - Speaking events 1974 (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Analysis of Bechtel/CPC Contract 1974 (Box 22)
  - Arms Control 1981-1983 (Box 22)
  - Big Rock Point Nuclear Plant
    - Chronological 1968-1979, 5 folders (Box 22)
    - Correspondence and press releases 1986-1992 (Box 22)
    - Effluents circa 1986-1989 (Box 22)
    - Press 1985-1992 (Box 22)
  - Bradford, Peter Commissioner, Nuclear Regulatory Commission 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Camp Grayling, National Guard 1989 (Box 22)
  - CBS-Radiation Programs Transcripts: "How Peaceful the Peaceful Atom," "Report on Radiation" and "Energy for the Future," 1970-1973 (Box 22)
  - "Citizens' Utility Boards: Because Utilities Bear Watching," by Beth Givens (Box 22)
  - Cherry, Myron 1977 (Box 22)
  - Clawson, Patrick M. 1974 (Box 22)
  - Clinch River Breeder Reactor 1982 (Box 22)
  - Comments 1981-1983 (Box 23)
  - Congressional testimony 1983 (Box 23)
    (Testimony of Billie Pirner Garde, Barbara G. Stamiris, and Mary P. Sinclair before the House Subcommittee on Energy and the Environment of the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs)
  - Construction Work in Progress 1982-1983 (Box 23)
  - Consumers Power Co.
    - Complaint: Consumers Power Company v. Combustion Engineering 1974 (Box 23)
    - "Consumers Power Company and the Nuclear Environment" by CPC 1970 (Box 23)
    - Correspondence re: "Nuclear Power and Public Concern" 1969 (Box 23)
    - Dishonesty 1972-1979 (Box 23)
    - Palisades Internal Memo 1972-1984 (Box 23)
    - Pipe Corrosion 1979-1982 (Box 23)
    - Soil Erosion Remediation 1982 (Box 23)
  - D.C. Cook Nuclear Power Plant repairs 1987-1989, 3 folders (Box 23)
  - Decommissioning 1985 (Box 23)
  - Demonstrations 1978-1979 (Box 23)
  - Dow Chemical Co.
    - Correspondence 1978-1994, 3 folders (Box 23)
    - Dioxin Pollution at Midland 1982-1984 (Box 23)
      (Andrea Wilson and Larry Fink)
    - Hazardous Waste Dumping 1982-1983, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Incinerator 1988-1992 (Box 23)
    - Macdonagh-Dumler, Jon 1990-1991 (Box 23)
    - Michigan Source Reduction Initiative 1998-1999 (Box 23)
    - Midland/Dow Community Advisory Panel
      - Agendas 1990-1996 (Box 23)
      - Joint meeting with Chemical Manufacturers Association September 24, 1999 (Box 23)
      - Media 1991 (Box 23)
      - Membership 1993-1994 (Box 23)
      - Minutes 1990-1996, 3 folders (Box 23)
      - Presentation of Dr. James Bus re: chlorine (Box 24)
      - Public Relations Materials 1990-1992 (Box 24)
      - Reports and Correspondence 1990-1996, 4 folders (Box 24)
    - Oreffice, Paul memo 1976 (Box 24)
    - Permit to Incinerate Low Level Radioactive Waste 1982 (Box 24)
    - President's Council on Sustainable Development 1994-1996 (Box 24)
    - Project XL: Environmental Excellence and Leadership 1995-1996 (Box 24)
    - Public Relations re: Environment 1989-1995, 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Toxics: Henry A. Waxman data 1990 (Box 24)
      (Chair of House Subcommittee on Health and the Environment on the EPA High-Risk Data)
  - Economics: Komanoff Study 1977 (Box 24)
  - Earthday rally Battle Creek April 19, 1990 (Box 24)
  - Fermi II
    - General 1985-1986 (Box 24)
      (Steve Sholly, Union of Concerned Scientists; Jennifer Puntenny and Mary Johnston; Michael J. Keegan, Safe Energy Coalition of Michigan; Michael Barrett, Mary Sinclair, Great Lakes Energy Alliance)
    - Operating License Public Hearing 1985 (Box 24)
    - Press Conference 1985 (Box 24)
  - Film on Nuclear Issues undated (Box 24)
  - Funding Ideas 1977 (Box 24)
  - Fundraising 1982-1989 (Box 24)
  - Gelman Sciences 1990 (Box 24)
  - Gelman Sciences: Chapters in Pollution Chronicle, draft (Box 24)
  - Globescope '93 "Implementing Sustainable Development in the Great Lakes Basin" by Patricia and John Hartig. Dearborn, MI March 18-20, 1993 (Box 24)
  - Gofman, John W. 1970-1976 (Box 24)
  - Governor Milliken's Nuclear Waste Committee Report 1980 (Box 24)
  - Governor's Conference on the Environment 1990 (Box 24)
  - Greenhouse effect 1988-1994 (Box 24)
  - Groundswell: An Energy Resource Journal 1979-1984 (Box 24)
  - Health Effects 1970-1978 (Box 24)
  - High Level Radioactive Waste 1977-1980 (Box 24)
  - Iowa Plan 1978 (Box 24)
  - Jackson Prison Contamination 1989-1990 (Box 24)
  - Jobs and the Environment 1973-1979 (Box 24)
  - Kellogg Foundation (Battle Creek Michigan): "Creating a Sustainable Environment: Reversing a Legacy of Neglect" National Fellows Forum December 3-6, 1989 (Box 25)
  - Legislation 1971-1979 (Box 25)
  - Legislative Investigation of Consumers Power Midland Plant 1985 (Box 25)
  - Licensing Reform 1984 (Box 25)
  - Low Level Radioactive Waste 1986-1988 (Box 25)
  - Ludington Pump Storage Geology Problem 1976 (Box 25)
  - Mailing Lists: Advocates and Media undated (Box 25)
  - Media
    - ABC News Correspondence 1980 (Box 25)
    - Advertising and Policy 1970-1983 (Box 25)
    - Deceptive Advertising 1973-1988 (Box 25)
    - Fairness Doctrine 1984-1985 (Box 25)
    - Federal Communications Commission complaint against WMPX 1971 (Box 25)
    - Nuclear Regulatory Commission News Releases 1980-1984 (Box 25)
  - Michigan Energy and Resource Research Assn. (MERRA) "Toward a Unified Michigan Energy Policy," 1980 (Box 25)
  - Michigan Business Review Correspondence re: Dow Chemical Co. 1972 (Box 25)
  - Michigan Low-level Radioactive Waste Authority
    - General 1985 (Box 25)
    - Midwest Interstate Low-level Radioactive Waste Compact Siting Plan 1987-1988 (Box 25)
    - Newsletters and correspondence 1989-1990 (Box 25)
  - Michigan Nuclear Plants 1974 (Box 25)
  - Michigan Public Service Commission 1980-1985 (Box 25)
  - Michigan Public Service Commission Legislative Report (Asperger): "Utility Regulation in Michigan," 1976 (Box 25)
  - Midland Chamber of Commerce 1972 (Box 25)
  - Midland, Michigan Task Force 2000 Report 1980 (Box 25)
  - Midland Plant
    - Consumers Power Co./Nuclear Regulatory Commission correspondence 1982 (Box 25)
    - Gas Conversion 1986 (Box 25)
    - Soil Settlement 1981-1984 (Box 25)
  - Midwest Interstate Low-level Radioactive Waste Commission 1982-1984 (Box 25)
  - Moral Issues, Nuclear Energy 1976-1978 (Box 25)
  - Nader, Ralph 1974-1976, 2 folders (Box 26)
  - National Urban League City Care Conference, Detroit 1979 (Box 26)
  - Nuclear energy literature 1973-1980 (Box 26)
  - Nuclear engineers' resignations: reasons 1974-1976 (Box 26)
  - Nuclear plant siting 1978-1981 (Box 26)
  - Nuclear power information booklets 1971-1980 (Box 26)
  - Nuclear Regulatory Commission Workshop on Site Cleanup Criteria 1992-1993 (Box 26)
  - Nuclear waste disposal 1980 (Box 26)
  - Nuclear waste transportation "Fallout on the Freeway: The Hazards of Transporting Radioactive Wastes in Michigan," a PIRGIM Report by Marion Anderson January 18, 1974 (Box 26)
  - Palisades Plant 1972-1982 (Box 26)
  - Power Plant Siting Bill 1978 (Box 26)
  - Press re: Midland Plant
    - Ann Arbor News 1984-1986 (Box 26)
    - Midland Daily News
      - Letters to the editor and paid ads 1969-1971 (Box 26)
      - Articles 1967-1986, 3 folders (Box 26)
    - Other Press 1972-1993 (Box 26)
  - Press Release re: Governor's Letter 1983 (Box 26)
  - Pro-Nuclear Rally, Midland Michigan October 1971 (Box 26)
  - Proposed Standards for Protection Against Radiation 1986-1987 (Box 26)
  - Public participation 1978-1979 (Box 26)
  - Radioactive and Toxic Waste Dumps in Michigan 1989-1990 (Box 26)
  - "Radioactive materials in California," 1978 (Box 26)
  - Radioactive Waste Transportation Hearing Statement 1981-1982 (Box 26)
  - Radioactive Wastes M. Sinclair Comments 1971-1980 (Box 26)
  - Resource Recovery Grants for Port Projects 1990 (Box 26)
  - Rural Electric Cooperatives 1978-1981 (Box 26)
  - Sabotage 1974 (Box 26)
  - Safe Energy Strategy Conference, Washington, D.C. 1986 (Box 27)
  - Safety 1965-1974, 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Shutdown Strategies 1987 (Box 27)
  - Solid Wastes circa 1977 (Box 27)
  - Special Joint Committee on Nuclear Energy of Michigan Legislature 1979-1980, 4 folders (Box 27)
  - Stamiris, Barbara: Summary Statements 1981-1983 (Box 27)
  - Stockholm Conference ECO Atomic Reactor Safety Hearings, Washington, DC 1972 (Box 27)
  - Stone & Webster Consulting Engineers 1981-1983 (Box 27)
  - Thermal Pollution, Lake Michigan 1970 (Box 27)
  - Three Mile Island 1979-1989 (Box 27)
  - Traxler Landfill site, Pinconning, MI 1990 (Box 27)
  - Viewgraphs: Low level nuclear waste undated (Box 27)
  - Wind Energy PURPA/Consumers Energy/U-6798 1982, 3 folders (Box 27)
  - Wood-fueled Power Generation 1977-1979 (Box 27)
  - World Energy Conference, Detroit 1974 (Box 27)
  - Wurtsmith Air Force Base Contamination 1990 (Box 27)
- Other Cases 1979-1985
  The Other Cases series (1.2 lin. ft.) contains documents related to legal proceedings other than the NRC licensing hearings for the Midland and Palisades plants. Sinclair's participation in disputes before the Michigan Public Service Commission, (which regulates utilities and electricity rates) is documented here. This series also contains papers related to Kelley v. Selin (high level nuclear waste storage at the Palisades plant), the Aeschliman case (sometimes called the "Table S.3 Case"), and the licensing of the Fermi II plant. All of these files are from the later accessions.
  - Bailey v. USDA, Injunction v. Fermi II for no public Environmental Statement, 1982 (Box 35)
  - Consumers Power Co.
    ("U" cases are before Michigan Public Service Commission)
    - Securities Act Shareholders Cases 1983-1984 (Box 35)
    - U-5979 Rate Case, GLEA objections to proposed order 1980 (Box 35)
    - U-6068 Security Case, Order and Correspondence 1979 (Box 35)
    - U-7512 Gas Cost Recovery Plan, Attorney General's Brief 1983 (Box 35)
    - U-7830 Rate Case
      - Correspondence 1982-1984 (Box 35)
      - Pleadings and Orders 1984-1986 (Box 35)
      - Testimony of Hugh Larkin, Jr. 1984 (Box 35)
    - U-8431 Compliance Filing 1985-1986 (Box 35)
  - Detroit Edison
    - Fermi II, FOIA Reports on Facilities 1984-1985, 2 folders (Box 35)
    - Fermi II, Misc. 1972-1985 (Box 35)
    - Fermi II, Petition to Intervene-Citizens for Employment and Energy undated (Box 35)
    - Fermi II, U-7660 Rate Case (Box 35)
  - Dow Chemical Co. v. Consumers Power Co.
    - Alfonse Aymond testimony October 17, 1984, 2 folders (Box 35)
      (CEO of Consumers Power)
    - Norman Saari testimony October 16, 1984 (Box 35)
      (Director of Public Relations for Consumers Power)
  - In re Joint Application of Consumers Power Co., Detroit Edison and Michigan Power Co. for authority to enter into a guaranty, 1989-1990, 2 folders (Box 35)
    (Ellen Beal, Chris Campbell, Public Issue Advocates)
  - Kelley v Selin
    - Fermi II 1979-1981 (Box 35)
    - Document Discovery/FOIA 1993-1994, 6 folders (Box 35)
      (Eric Glitzenstein, lawyer)
    - Frank J. Kelley, Attorney General's Oral Argument October 11, 1994 (Box 36)
    - Motion to Supplement Record on Review September 24, 1993 (Box 36)
    - Research: Dry Cask Storage, 3 folders (Box 36)
  - Saginaw Valley Nuclear Study Group v. U.S. Atomic Energy Commission (Aeschliman case)
    - Appellate brief for Intervenor Consumers Power Co. May 1, 1974 (Box 36)
    - Supreme Court brief in opposition to writ of certiorari 1976 (Box 36)
    - District Court pleadings 1978-1979 (Box 36)
- Audio-visual material